Register of the George H. Kerr Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George H. Kerr papers,
1943-1951
XX381
Kerr, George H., 1911-
7 manuscript boxes (3.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, notes, press summaries, clippings, and writings, relating to political and economic conditions in Formosa under Japanese rule, transfer of Formosa to China in 1945, Formosan rebellion against Chinese rule in 1947, American foreign policy regarding Formosa, and political and economic conditions in the Ryukyu Islands after World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Biographical Note
1911 Nov. 7 Born
1935-1937 Student, Japan
1937-1940 English teacher, Taipei, Taiwan
1942-1943 Analyst and consultant on Formosa, U.S. Department of War
1944-1946 Director, Formosa Research Unit, Naval School of Military Government and Administration, U.S. Navy, Columbia University, New York
1946-1947 Foreign service staff officer and vice consul, U.S. Department of State, Taipei, Taiwan
1947-1949 Lecturer, University of Washington
1949-1950 Lecturer, Stanford University and University of California at Berkeley
1950-1955? Research Associate, Hoover Institution
1952 Published The Ryukyu Islands: A Preliminary Checklist of Reference Materials Arranged Alphabetically (with Higa Shuncho and others)
1953 Published Ryukyu Kingdom and Province Before 1945
1958 Published Okinawa: The History of an Island People
1959 Published Science Information Services in Japan, a Brief Survey
1961 Published Bibliography of the Ryukyus
1965 Published Formosa Betrayed
1974 Published Formosa: Licensed Revolution and the Home Rule Movement, 1895-1945
1986 Published The Taiwan Confrontation Crisis
1992 Aug. 27 Died, Honolulu, Hawaii
Scope and Content Note
The George H. Kerr Papers provide information about economic and political affairs in Taiwan in the 1930s and 1940s, Taiwan's transition from Japanese rule before and during World War II to postwar Chinese rule, Taiwanese rebellion against Chinese rule in 1947, and U.S. foreign policy toward Taiwan. Some information about economic and political conditions in Okinawa and the Ryukyu Islands after World War II is also included.
The series CHRONOLOGICAL FILE OF EVENTS IN TAIWAN covers the period during which Kerr served as U.S. vice consul at Taipei. It consists chiefly of translated local press reports, many of which were issued by the United States Information Service, Taipei, and handwritten chronologies of local events in Taiwan. Some of the chronologies are written in composition notebooks that span several months in a single notebook; these are filed under the first month listed in the notebook.
Most of the material in the SUBJECT FILE series was collected during Kerr's service as a Taiwan specialist with the U.S. military during World War II. Included are translations of selected chapters of Taiwan Jijō (Conditions in Taiwan), 1939, and Taiwan Keizai Nempō (Taiwan Economic Annual Report), 1943, prepared at the Military Government Translation Center of the Naval School of Military Government and Administration at Columbia University. Also included are outlines of a series of lectures that were directed toward U.S. civil affairs officers assigned to Taiwan. The dates provided in the container list for this series are limited because many of the documents do not bear dates, some have only a translation date, and others have only a publication date. The few photographs available depict Taiwan's geographic features.
The CLIPPINGS FILE series also relates primarily to Taiwan, with the vast bulk dated 1950. The articles were cut from English-language newspapers in the U.S., such as the San Francisco Chronicle, Chinese World (San Francisco), and the New York Times.
The UNIVERSITY SEMINAR FILE series relates to courses on East Asia at the Hoover Institution and the University of California in which Kerr served as instructor or co-instructor. The files are incomplete, consisting of miscellaneous course materials and a few student papers. Other student papers are interfiled in the SUBJECT FILE series.
In addition to material in the WRITINGS series, some notes and drafts that were probably written by Kerr are interfiled with other documents in the SUBJECT FILE series. In the series CHRONOLOGICAL FILE OF EVENTS IN TAIWAN, a few brief memoranda by Kerr are interfiled from January 1947, and syllabi in the UNIVERSITY SEMINAR FILE series were probably written by him.
Most of the papers in this collection are in English; a few are in Japanese. Folders consisting entirely of material in Japanese are indicated in the container list.
A major portion of Kerr's research collection is held by the East Asian Library at the University of California at Berkeley; additional Kerr papers are held at the 2-28 Memorial Museum Archives in Taiwan and the Okinawa Prefectural Archives.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
United States. Dept. of State.; Okinawa-ken (Japan); Ryukyu Islands.; Taiwan.; Taiwan--Economic conditions.; Taiwan--Foreign relations--United States.; Taiwan--History.; Taiwan--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Taiwan.; Japan.; United States. Consulate (Taipei, Taiwan)
Occupations
Diplomats--United States.
Container List
- Writings, 1947-1948. (Box 1)
  Draft and notes, arranged chronologically by title
  - Report on CNRRA and UNRRA operations, 1947 February. (Folder 1: 1)
    Notes
  - Memoranda on the Taiwan crisis: Taipei and Nanking, 1947 March. (Folder 1: 2-4)
  - "Industry, 1945-1947," 1948. (Folder 1: 5)
    Draft. Typescript
- Chronological File of Events in Taiwan, 1945-1947. (Box 1-2)
  Chronologies, clippings, drafts, memoranda, notes, pamphlets, translated press reports, arranged chronologically
  - 1945 December (Folder 1: 6)
  - 1946
    - January (Folder 1: 7-8)
    - February (Folder 1: 9-10)
    - March (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    - April (Folder 2: 3)
    - May (Folder 2: 4-5)
    - June (Folder 2: 6)
    - July (Folder 2: 7)
    - August (Folder 2: 8)
    - October (Folder 2: 9)
    - December (Folder 2: 10-11)
  - 1947
    - January (Folder 2: 12)
    - February (Folder 2: 13)
    - March (Folder 2: 14)
    - April (Folder 2: 15)
    - August (Folder 2: 16)
    - October (Folder 2: 17)
- Subject File, 1900-1950(bulk 1939-1946). (Box 3-7)
  Charts, clippings, laws, letters, lists, maps, notes, outlines, photographs, printed matter, reports, translations of publications, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Aborigines, n.d. (Folder 3: 1)
    In Japanese
  - Administration
    - Associations, n.d. (Folder 3: 2)
    - Glossary of terms, divisions, charts, 1946 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Local
      - Organizations, 1943-1946 (Folder 3: 4)
      - Representation, 1946 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Organization, 1946 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Personnel problems, classes, hierarchy, n.d. (Folder 3: 7)
    - Police system (Japanese period), n.d. (Folder 3: 8)
  - Administrative organs and gun administration (Japanese period), 1939-1941 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Agriculture
    - General, 1939-1940 (Folder 3: 10-12)
    - Formosan Agricultural Review
      - 1940 November issue. (Folder 3: 13)
      - Contents of volumes 27 to 35, 1944 (Folder 3: 14)
    - Organization, farmers associations, etc., 1939-1944 (Folder 3: 15)
    - Policy, crop rotation, n.d. (Folder 3: 16)
    - Related industries, raw materials, n.d. (Folder 3: 17)
    - Rice, 1933-1940 (Folder 3: 18)
    - Sugar industry, 1938-1946 (Folder 3: 19-20)
    - Tea, 1939? (Folder 3: 21)
  - Bibliographies, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Bibliographies, 1943-1944 (Contd.) (Folder 4: 1-2)
  - Commerce--Commodity prices and wages, Jijō, 1939? (Folder 4: 3)
  - Communications
    - Japanese postal laws, 1940? (Folder 4: 4-5)
    - Postal service, 1939 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Radio, 1940 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Conversion tables and terminology, 1944 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Economics
    - Banks and other enterprises (Formosa), 1940 (Folder 4: 9-10)
    - Cost of living, 1946-1947 (Folder 4: 11)
    - Development
      - General, 1949 (Folder 4: 12)
      - Report for British trade mission, 1946 (Folder 4: 13)
    - Mitsui interests in Formosa, 1941 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Monopolies, 1945-1946, from manuscript prepared by Japanese, retained by Chinese government for the year, 1946? (Folder 4: 15)
    - Taiwan Keizai Nempo, 1943 (Folder 4: 16)
    - Trade and finance (Taiwan Jijō), 1939? (Folder 4: 17)
  - Education, 1939 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Factionalism, leadership problems, 1949 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Finance
    - General
      - General, 1940-1949 (Folder 4: 20)
      - Index to manuscript on finance, prepared by Japanese, retained by Chinese government, 1946 (Box-folder 5: 1)
      - Notes on finance, banking, Chinese actions (from conversation with Suzuki, et al.), 1946 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Banking, 1944 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Currency, 1944 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Fisheries, n.d. (Folder 5: 5)
  - Forestry
    - General, 1939-1943? (Folder 5: 6-7)
    - Camphor, n.d. (Folder 5: 8)
  - Formosa
    - Bibliography project, 1950 (Folder 5: 9)
    - Development of Hainan Island, 1943-1949 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Geography
    - General, 1947-1948 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Coal field areas, North Formosa, 1936 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Kōtōsho (Botel Tobago), 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 13)
    - Maps, photographs, 1941 (Folder 5: 14)
    - Meteorology, weather, 1939-1946 (Folder 5: 15)
    - Place names, 1944 (Folder 5: 16)
    - Rivers, n.d. (Folder 5: 17)
  - History to 1895, 1947-1949 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Industry
    - Associations, 1943 (Folder 5: 19-21)
    - KMT [Kuomintang]
      - Control, 1946-1947 (Folder 5: 22)
      - Government in industry, 1946 (Folder 5: 23)
    - Manufacturing, 1939? (Folder 5: 24)
    - Paper, 1946 (Folder 5: 25)
    - Plants, 1945 takeover conditions, 1945 (Folder 5: 26)
    - Rehabilitation, 1946-1947 (Folder 5: 27)
    - Research, science, 1943? (Folder 5: 28)
    - Under Japan, n.d. (Folder 5: 29)
  - Investigation of marine product industry in the Pescadores, 1930 (Folder 5: 30)
  - Irrigation--Kanan system, 1932-1940 (Folder 5: 31)
  - Japan--Maene's memorandum regarding rehabilitation, 1949 (Folder 5: 32)
  - Japanese government organization, n.d. (Folder 5: 33)
  - Legal affairs--Japanese legislation, 1900-1944 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Marine industry, 1939? (Folder 6: 2)
  - Military affairs--Japanese army, 1942 (Folder 6: 3)
  - New books, etc., 1950 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Notes for and from MIS memos, letters, 1943 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Okinawa, 1946-1949 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Okinawans in Taiwan, n.d. (Folder 6: 7)
  - Personnel of concerns, 1940 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Pescadores, 1946 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Place names and surnames, n.d. (Folder 6: 10)
  - Population--Cities, 1940? (Folder 6: 11)
  - Ports and harbors
    - Keelung, 1946 (Folder 6: 12)
    - Rehabilitation, 1945 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Postwar Japanese in Formosa, n.d. (Folder 6: 14)
  - Propaganda and public information, 1945-1947 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Property survey--Japanese properties, 1944 (Folder 6: 16-17)
  - Public works, 1939 (Folder 6: 18-20)
  - Resources
    - Mining, coal, 1936 (Folder 6: 21)
    - Power development, n.d. (Folder 6: 22)
  - Separatism, independence, resistance to outside control, n.d. (Folder 6: 23)
  - Sino-Japanese war, transfer to Japan (Pescadores), n.d. (Folder 6: 24)
  - Takeover report prepared for Chen Yin government, 1946 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Transport--Railways, 1938-1947? (Folder 7: 3)
  - Treaties, agreements, etc., as legal basis of empire, n.d. (Folder 7: 4)
  - Wei Tao-ming (Gov.) anti-American speech, 1947 Dec. 3 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Who's who, 1945-1948 (Folder 7: 6-8)
- Clippings, 1947-1951(bulk 1950). (Box 7)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - American aid (other than military), 1950 (Folder 7: 9)
  - China
    - Chinese Communists and the U.N., 1950 (Folder 7: 10)
    - McCarthy, Kohlberg; China lobby, 1950 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Formosa
    - American
      - And other diplomatic, consular representation, 1950 (Folder 7: 12)
      - Military aid and strategic estimates, 1949-1950 (Folder 7: 13)
    - And Britain, 1950 (Folder 7: 14)
    - And Russia, 1950 (Folder 7: 15)
    - And SCAP--Representation at Tokyo, etc., 1950 (Folder 7: 16)
    - And Tibet, Philippine Islands, Indo-China, n.d. (Folder 7: 17)
    - As American domestic political issue, 1950 (Folder 7: 18)
    - As refuge for mainland Chinese, 1950 (Folder 7: 19)
    - Chiang Kai-shek--Activities, policies, history, rivals; Mme. Chiang, 1950 (Folder 7: 20)
    - Communist China's preparations for military invasion; defense activities, 1950 (Folder 7: 21)
    - Communist Chinese attitudes, demands, proclamations, 1949-1951 (Folder 7: 22)
    - Defections, subversion, retreats, spy hysteria, 1950 (Folder 7: 23)
    - June 27 declaration and consequences, n.d. (Folder 7: 24)
    - KMT [Kuomintang]
      - Actions, announcements, etc., having propaganda value, 1950 (Folder 7: 25)
      - Government
        - Activities, policies, 1950 (Folder 7: 26)
        - Organization on Formosa, 1950 (Folder 7: 27)
    - MacArthur, Douglas. "L'Affaire MacArthur," 1950 (Folder 7: 28)
    - Self-determination issue, nationalist sentiment, 1947-1950 (Folder 7: 29)
    - Sovereignty issue, 1950 (Folder 7: 30)
    - "Third Force" idea, 1950 (Folder 7: 31)
    - Trade with mainland, 1948-1950 (Folder 7: 32)
    - U.N. issue and action, 1949-1950 (Folder 7: 33)
    - U.S. policy (after 1945), 1950 crisis and conflict, 1949-1950 (Folder 7: 34)
  - Leadership--Chiang-Li feud, other rivals, 1950 (Folder 7: 35)
- University Seminar File, 1949-1952. (Box 7)
  Book lists, enrollment cards, memoranda, printed matter, student papers, syllabi, arranged numerically by course number
  - 276, Nationalism, socialism, democracy in contemporary Far East, 1950? (Folder 7: 36)
  - 283, Dependent areas and world politics I: Island areas, 1950-1952 (Folder 7: 37)
  - 284, Dependent areas and world politics II: Southeast Asia, 1950-1951 (Folder 7: 38)
  - S192, American and the expansion of the Japanese Empire, 1949-1950 (Folder 7: 39)
  - S193, Japan in Formosa, 1950 (Folder 7: 40)